[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339664", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Marge decided to sell what snack food?", "answer": "Pretzels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390b6", "question": "With which instrument is jazz musician Charlie Mingus principally associated?", "answer": "Double Bass", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a387", "question": "What is the capital of Iceland?", "answer": "Reykjavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339138", "question": "Whose alias is \"The Man of Bronze\" in popular literature?", "answer": "Doc Savage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb43", "question": "What is the only bonus item, that dances around the maze, Ms. Pac-Man can eat that is not a type of fruit?", "answer": "Pretzel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c976", "question": "What does an ombrometer measure?", "answer": "Rainfall", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e1fefe83fe1f2a824b9b", "question": "What was Hitler\u2019s primary justification for invading Russia?", "answer": "Germany needed more space for its population.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c529877e98cb977789ac", "question": "The Griffith Observatory is located where?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d9", "question": "What city boasted the world's first subway line?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5af25aa1b63e5727cf5a4855", "question": "Which song was featured in the 1991 film \"Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves\" and held the number one spot in the UK singles chart for 16 weeks?", "answer": "(Everything I Do) I Do It for You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c2", "question": "What is Albumen the correct term for?", "answer": "Egg White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5902a0a9cad1ec93f27df76f", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the AeroPress?", "answer": "Alan Adler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c1620775fa611bce67c3", "question": "Dysmorphia is a mental disorder characterized by what?", "answer": "The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed. The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed, and therefore, warrants exceptional measures to hide or fix it", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b96", "question": "What actor built a working full\u00adsize painter's studio for himself in preparation for his role as a famous artist?", "answer": "Ed Harris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eaccaf83302ff91e46473", "question": "What part of a wine bottle is the punt?", "answer": "The indentation in the base", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339079", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Turandot\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe767c5eec85e375820b296", "question": "In which country was volcano boarding invented?", "answer": "Nicaragua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a552b23e1c6f9840ba319b", "question": "Which country has the calling code 82?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd96f4a23c87fd04dd15e41", "question": "Who were the first people known to celebrate the New Year?", "answer": "Babylonians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c435", "question": "What is the only bone in the human body that doesn't connect with any other?", "answer": "Hyoid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3f", "question": "What was the last name of Bill Murray\u2019s character\u2019s platoon Sergeant in the movie \"Stripes\"?", "answer": "Hulka", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a017", "question": "What actor was the narrator in the movie \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "Stephen Fry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd82", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Ebirah?", "answer": "Shrimp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6f", "question": "What was the name of Rhett and Scarlett\u2019s daughter in \"Gone With the Wind\"?", "answer": "Bonnie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4a978261d1b4d384d5d685", "question": "What is the study of grasses called?", "answer": "Agrostology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f16abaf7c52aae91cc07e0", "question": "What is Australia's highest mainland mountain?", "answer": "Mount Kosciuszko", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a988", "question": "What city named its airport after John Foster Dulles?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9f", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was Dorothy's uncle's name?", "answer": "Henry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a1a1c612f2a7826b9b8715", "question": "What milk is Pecorino cheese made from?", "answer": "Ewe's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdd5e5d0499cffc60b84234", "question": "According to the Bible, who requested the head of John the Baptist on a silver platter?", "answer": "Herodias", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ae860a84007905755f79e8f", "question": "What year was Julius Caeser assassinated", "answer": "44 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63d", "question": "A Calorie is a measurement of what?", "answer": "Energy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d4", "question": "What does a red flag mean in auto racing?", "answer": "Stop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe36b250ada16518afdc039", "question": "From which country did the troll doll originate?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfaebcf3977a46e7ce448", "question": "Bees have 5 what?", "answer": "Eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af3", "question": "According to the lyrics of the Counting Crows song \"Mr. Jones\", what rock legend does the singer want to be?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339921", "question": "Actress Carrie Fisher and singer Edie Brickell have both been married to what musician?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f1a", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Catherine Keener and Sandra Bullock?", "answer": "Harper Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16878f7c52aae91cc07c7", "question": "\"Cardice\" is another term for what?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fed28b9ec223966ae8f890d", "question": "What decade is the hit single \"Sultans Of Swing\" by Dire Straits from?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1edc4145fb2946670738a", "question": "What is added to vanilla ice cream to make New Zealand\u2019s popular hokey-pokey flavor?", "answer": "Honeycomb toffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4b7a706d333868d34d6f9", "question": "Who was the last Emperor of the Austro-Hungarian Empire?", "answer": "Karl I (or Charles I)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a0", "question": "What is -459.67 F also know as?", "answer": "Absolute Zero", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa3f9dc73aa70ea0b70b01", "question": "What does the Japanese term \"Sandai Wagyu\" translate as?", "answer": "Three Big Beefs (Sandai Wagyu are \"the three big beefs\" - Matsusaka, \u014cmi and the most-famous of all, Kobe.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28b", "question": "Who is the lead singer of Metallica?", "answer": "James Hetfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd82125d0de9af39e9d46a3", "question": "Who founded the first McDonald's?", "answer": "Richard and Maurice McDonald", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe77602eec85e375820b315", "question": "Where is the tallest mosque in the world?", "answer": "Morocco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339091", "question": "In Greek mythology, what was Hades the god of?", "answer": "Underworld", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e4", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"Hello, beautiful. No ring, I see. So you are only arranged to be married.\"?", "answer": "Apu Nahasapeemapetilon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecf", "question": "What animated film begins in Shiverpool, Antarctica?", "answer": "Surf's Up", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a96f", "question": "What US city is named for a Roman general famed for leaving his troops and retiring to his farm?", "answer": "Cincinnati", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c848", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the Sertoli cells?", "answer": "The testes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ad", "question": "What is the official monetary unit of the nation of Thailand?", "answer": "Baht", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa84d73838c5c8a417f3c", "question": "What element makes up about 90% of the known universe?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9b8b9364247bf200fb883", "question": "In the 1983 film \"National Lampoon's Vacation\", where were the Griswold's headed on their cross country trip?", "answer": "Walley World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601debe96b1208747aa7e9d7", "question": "Which famous entrepreneur is credited with inventing the weekend?", "answer": "Henry Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81fdfd0de9af39e9d469a", "question": "What year did Amazon.com make its first sale?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c24b", "question": "How many wings does a bee have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbf0b6ce05a3942286efa", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Material Girl\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c565", "question": "How many toes does a pig have on each foot?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a058", "question": "Adrenalize, Retro Active, and Pyromania are albums from which British hard rock band?", "answer": "Def Leppard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa5623c73aa70ea0b70b28", "question": "In which state of the United States would you find Fort Knox?", "answer": "Kentucky", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc76", "question": "Who was responsible for creating Reese's Peanut Butter Cups in 1928?", "answer": "H. B. Reese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed9", "question": "How many times did Mary Queen of Scots get married?", "answer": "Three Times", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f1683df7c52aae91cc07c4", "question": "What is the fear of light flashes known as?", "answer": "Selaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f0", "question": "What US state has been governed by James Polk and Austin Peay?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015fd0afe83fe1f2a824c49", "question": "Which personality in the Bible got blinded by a bright light on his way to Damascus?", "answer": "Saul", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b473", "question": "What duo first published the \"Michelin Guide\" in 1900?", "answer": "Andre and Edouard Michelin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac9d", "question": "How many of Henry VIII's wives were executed?", "answer": "Two", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbde96ce05a3942286ee4", "question": "Who was the creator of \"Star Trek\"?", "answer": "Gene Roddenberry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d7", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role in the film 'The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a979661d1b4d384d5d686", "question": "In the world of tennis, who was the first to win all four Grand Slams in the same year?", "answer": "Don Budge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec8c56ec223966ae8f8848", "question": "The 1994 \"Leon\" was the motion-picture debut of which one of its stars?", "answer": "Natalie Portman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be12", "question": "When going directly to jail, a Monopoly player is commanded not to do what two things?", "answer": "Do not pass Go, Do not collect $200.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb57b35dad637d903c880a", "question": "What material did early Venetians use to construct the foundations of their buildings?", "answer": "Wood (Venice's buildings were built on marshy mud and sand.  The wood petrified due to the lack of oxygen in the marshy soil.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008e1ccf842fa4c4ba96af", "question": "Who was radio's \"All-American Boy\"?", "answer": "Jack Armstrong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff20f6631a458464a93c433", "question": "Who wrote the play \"A Streetcar Named Desire\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b4", "question": "Anthony Robert McMillan is more famous as who?", "answer": "Robbie Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90e", "question": "What major river runs through Dublin?", "answer": "Liffey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fff", "question": "What British TV series featured Saffron and Bubble?", "answer": "Absolutely Fabulous", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde4966c6c6b019850c9a6f", "question": "Easter was named from what Anglo-Saxon goddess?", "answer": "Eostre", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab963a86faa38a764be51d", "question": "What was the original cost of the first Ford Model T, sold in 1909?", "answer": "$825", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae3", "question": "What is the capital of Cuba?", "answer": "Havana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc38eec223966ae8f887f", "question": "Who won the 1981 Grammy for \"Record of the Year\"?", "answer": "Christopher Cross for \"Sailing\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ac", "question": "Which city was the first to own a subway system?", "answer": "London", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ad", "question": "Which country were the 1952 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339780", "question": "The name of which Norwegian Black Metal band translates into Dark Fortress?", "answer": "Dimmu Borgir", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a551be3e1c6f9840ba318f", "question": "Corfu is part of which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a7", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Nepal?", "answer": "Everest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c887", "question": "Chemically, what kind of acid is stomach acid?", "answer": "Hydrochloric acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0f", "question": "What is comedian Jon Stewart's full birth name?", "answer": "Jonathan Stuart Leibowitz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe5", "question": "What actress wrote the autobiography \"Call Me Anna\"?", "answer": "Patty Duke", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339203", "question": "Who finds E.T.?", "answer": "Elliott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76941eec85e375820b2af", "question": "In which sea would you find the Cayman Islands?", "answer": "Caribbean Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f8ed01dd7bf43be5e849", "question": "What is the largest three-digit prime number?", "answer": "997", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84f", "question": "What physical fitness practice is named for the Sanskrit word for \"union\"?", "answer": "Yoga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac0", "question": "Allan \"Rocky\" Lane provided the voice of what 1960's sitcom title character?", "answer": "Mister Ed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af1", "question": "What sporting competition was the focus of the 2007 film \"Balls of Fury\"?", "answer": "Ping Pong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b6d", "question": "Who won a Best Supporting Actor Oscar for the 2004 movie \"Million Dollar Baby\"?", "answer": "Morgan Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339334", "question": "What was Lucille Ball's TV nickname?", "answer": "The First Lady of Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3d", "question": "What singer's autobiography was titled \"Man in Black\"?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a4", "question": "What Michael Keaton film gives mortals a peek into a Handbook for the Recently Deceased?", "answer": "Beetlejuice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb28", "question": "In baseball score-keeping, what number represents the third baseman's position?", "answer": "5", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5a3f6ce05a3942286e0b", "question": "\"Life is Beautiful\" has been named one of the top-five favorite films of which prominent figure?", "answer": "Pope John Paul II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e0", "question": "Which famous actress was born Vera Jane Palmer?", "answer": "Jayne Mansfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0f", "question": "What was the name of Paul and Jamie\u2019s dog on the TV show \"Mad About You\"?", "answer": "Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c250", "question": "What do you call an animal that eats both plants and animals?", "answer": "An Omnivore", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338afc", "question": "Which character killed Uncle Tom?", "answer": "Simon Legree", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb5d095dad637d903c8821", "question": "Which U.S. Interstate highway is the longest?", "answer": "I-90", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cad", "question": "Who completed his famous bird paintings in 1839?", "answer": "John J. Audubon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a3", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named for Paris?", "answer": "Lutetium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e6a906d333868d34d734", "question": "Why did President Theodore Roosevelt ban Christmas trees from the White House?", "answer": "Because tree harvesting was depleting the country's forrests", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa7", "question": "Frank Zappa's 1979 album \"Sheik Yerboutti\" was a salute to what band's 1976 hit?", "answer": "KC and the Sunshine Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e2", "question": "How did Buffalo Bill die?", "answer": "Kidney failure", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f76", "question": "Which Shakespearean character has the most lines?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba1d3874c93a3298b212c", "question": "How many distinct campaigns did the Crusades have?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c737", "question": "What does a lepidopterist study or collect?", "answer": "Butterflies", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a456", "question": "How many provinces are there in Canada?", "answer": "10", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bdb", "question": "Which author won the Booker Prize 1986 for the novel \"The Old Devils\"?", "answer": "Kingsley Amis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078c3d0eee65b76b9f2670", "question": "Britain\u2019s Bantam Battalions were composed of what kind of soldiers?", "answer": "Undersized (The British created a battalion for undersized volunteers, nicknamed the Bantams - a type of small, ferocious bird.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f164bb2f9b80650dbe7f92d", "question": "Which Marvel Cinematic Universe character was frozen in ice for 66 years?", "answer": "Captain America", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173fab44491cbd7c5a17b4", "question": "What general commanded the American Expeditionary Forces on the Western Front during World War I?", "answer": "John Joseph \"Black Jack\" Pershing GCB", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990afb4b72eedf883a8c709", "question": "Where were the Pillars of Hercules located?", "answer": "Strait of Gibraltar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909caddbb53d1af658864d3", "question": "What ABC Original Movie, starring Jenny McCarthy, air on December 10, 2006?", "answer": "Santa Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe939a66bd93ce3a4e5f68f", "question": "What term describes the center of gravity of the Earth and moon?", "answer": "Barycenter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa74c73838c5c8a417f36", "question": "What is the fear of long words known as?", "answer": "Hippopotomostrosesquippedaliophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b2f901dd7bf43be5e7a5", "question": "What team retired Michael Jordan\u2019s jersey despite him never playing for them?", "answer": "Miami Heat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa43", "question": "What geographic term describes a hill with sharply sloping sides and a flat top?", "answer": "Butte", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c349", "question": "In computer science, what does the acronym GIGO stand for?", "answer": "Garbage In, Garbage Out", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ea", "question": "What does a player generally use for a long fairway shot in golf - a wood or an iron?", "answer": "Wood", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c7c49076251badbead5", "question": "Which newspaper incorrectly reported Thomas E. Dewey defeated Harry S. Truman in the 1948 U.S. Presidential Election?", "answer": "Chicago Daily Tribune -- Now known as Chicago Tribune, it had once referred to Truman as a \"nincompoop\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fa", "question": "What were the names of rival gangs in \"West Side Story\"?", "answer": "The Jets and The Sharks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aceb", "question": "Who was the first Holy Roman Emperor?", "answer": "Charlemagne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c83a", "question": "What irrational number is the base of a natural logarithm?", "answer": "e", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb60", "question": "In 1973, who became the first Latino ballplayer inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Roberto Clemente", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da4", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"The Pelican Brief\"?", "answer": "Robert Culp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c455877e98cb9777899d", "question": "Where is the oldest brewery in North America?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b50c", "question": "What chessman makes an L-shaped move?", "answer": "The knight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb62", "question": "What product used the advertising slogan, \"Where's your moustache?\"", "answer": "Milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3e", "question": "What teenage trauma did Ben Folds commemorate in his 1997 hit \"Brick\"?", "answer": "His girlfriend's abortion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339366", "question": "What actress played James Bond's love interest in the 2006 movie \"Casino Royale\"?", "answer": "Eva Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c3", "question": "The Chevy model known as the Camaro was originally intended to be called what?", "answer": "Panther", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d3d42596a59cbdfbd39e", "question": "What was the name of the first computer search engine?", "answer": "Archie", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a461", "question": "The Angkor Wat temple is featured on what Asian country's flag?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba58", "question": "What comedian provided the voice for the AFLAC duck in TV commercials until he was let go?", "answer": "Gilbert Gottfried", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc4046de0eb824d4052f0", "question": "In what state is it a law for apple pie to be served with cheese?", "answer": "Vermont -- According to a 1999 law, apple pie must be served with a least one once of cheddar cheese, ice cream or milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b867", "question": "In which sport do you \"shag\" flies?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fc854f3abc30a8194e188ab", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Black Hawk Down\"?", "answer": "Mark Bowden", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2b", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 608?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbef", "question": "Who designed Madonna's infamous cone-bra?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c185", "question": "What is the fear of the Sun called?", "answer": "Heliophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf97", "question": "What nationality was the explorer Vitus Bering?", "answer": "Danish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a454", "question": "Doha is the capital of which Middle-Eastern country?", "answer": "Qatar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eb016f83302ff91e46498", "question": "Who is often referred to as the \"Fifth Beatle\"?", "answer": "Stu Sutcliffe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b89", "question": "What is the number of thieves that Alibaba had?", "answer": "40", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8e5", "question": "What's the collective noun for a group of gulls?", "answer": "Colony", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdff5bc1cf6db9ac4808ced", "question": "What city is home to the Spanish Steps?", "answer": "Rome, Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6003952057a0e35c43f83892", "question": "Any color plus black is called what?", "answer": "A shade", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b983", "question": "The synodic month starts with a new what?", "answer": "Moon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa5730c73aa70ea0b70b32", "question": "What is the state motto for California?", "answer": "Eureka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339537", "question": "Where does Grace work in the TV show \"Grace Under Fire\"?", "answer": "At the oil refinery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea33deff048f679a45aaf1", "question": "Nikola Tesla started his career working for which later rival?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a164", "question": "Who is Reginald Kenneth Dwight otherwise known as?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f5", "question": "What TV mother has presided over the longest-running American sitcom ever?", "answer": "Marge Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339219", "question": "What actor is known as \"The Fonz\"?", "answer": "Henry Winkler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4edc106d333868d34d770", "question": "What do you call the moveable indicator on a Ouija board which is shaped like a heart?", "answer": "Planchette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3d", "question": "What is the title object of the 2006 film \"Brick\" a brick of?", "answer": "Heroin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f1e16682715b82711ce4", "question": "What is the name of the strait located between the Italy and Albania?", "answer": "Straits of Otranto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aecb", "question": "In 1553, Lady Jane Grey was Queen of England for how many days?", "answer": "9", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d1", "question": "How many wings does a bee have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d0", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of Patty and Selma's iguana?", "answer": "Jub-Jub", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a541", "question": "Which US state is home to Crater Lake National Park?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969f", "question": "Who is Brian mistaken for in the 1979 movie \"Life of Brian\"?", "answer": "The Messiah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c981", "question": "Amazon river dolphins, also known as pink river dolphins, are also referred to as what?", "answer": "Botos or bufeos", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde50efc6c6b019850c9a8b", "question": "In the Bible, what does Gideon's name mean?", "answer": "Tree cutter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdab5370b8cce1e6fda704b", "question": "How can you tell if cranberries are ripe?", "answer": "They bounce like rubber balls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a531", "question": "What US city is located on the shores of Rapid Creek?", "answer": "Rapid City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9f", "question": "Tashkent is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b35", "question": "In 1976, who was the first woman to become a national network news co-anchor?", "answer": "Barbara Walters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133997a", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Lenny and Homer were members of what secret society?", "answer": "Stonecutters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d48", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Dragonfly\"?", "answer": "Alison Lohman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133890c", "question": "What was the sequel to \"Little Women\"?", "answer": "Good Wives", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f2", "question": "What US state has been governed by Evan Mecham and Bruce Babbitt?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3df", "question": "What year was Native American war leader, Crazy Horse born?", "answer": "1842", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339864", "question": "In Disney's \"Pinocchio\", what animal does Pinocchio begin to turn into after he reaches Pleasure Island?", "answer": "Donkey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa8ad6ce05a3942286ed5", "question": "In the film \"Davy Crockett, King of the Wild Frontier\", who played the role of Davy's pal, George Russel?", "answer": "Buddy Ebsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6f", "question": "\"Staying Alive\", the sequel to the movie \"Saturday Night Fever\", was released what year?", "answer": "1983", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd4c877e98cb97778a34", "question": "What was the first country to declare internet a legal right?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173fdc44491cbd7c5a17b7", "question": "John the Baptist's father was who?", "answer": "The father of John the Baptist was Zechariah.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062bfac9d816e292245c27", "question": "What artist is best known for a painting of his mother?", "answer": "James McNeil Whistler's most famous painting is \"Arrangement in Black and Grey No.1\".  It is commonly known \"Whistler's Mother\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bd05cb540191c55fd523fb5", "question": "What video game, that peaked in the late 2000's, got people to try stumping a cartoon genie?", "answer": "Akinator", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3f", "question": "Which famous poem includes the line \"I am the master of my fate, I am the captain of my soul\"?", "answer": "Invictus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60121bae63c99d48cd169b0f", "question": "An ailurophile is a lover of what?", "answer": "Cats -- \"Ailurophile\" comes from the Greek \"ailouros\", for cat, combined with \"-phile\", the suffix for love.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02e", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", what is Stewie's favorite TV show?", "answer": "Jolly Farm Revue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22b", "question": "What kind of dough is usually used to make an eclair?", "answer": "Choux dough", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b6cde662d71a5365100e", "question": "The book \"Lord of Light\", was written by whom?", "answer": "Roger Zelazny", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acab", "question": "What month in 1912 saw the Titanic go down?", "answer": "April", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e94cf395ea27d7a1303aece", "question": "Which rapper went platinum with his 2014 Album \"2014 Forest Hills Drive\"?", "answer": "J. Cole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9df", "question": "Which branch of science is concerned with the study of matter and energy?", "answer": "Physics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb81", "question": "What Christian denomination was begun by John Wesley in 1738?", "answer": "Methodist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c939", "question": "In what organ of the body is insulin produced?", "answer": "Pancreas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5906809aff9c0647b50a808d", "question": "What sporting legend was born Cassius Marcellus Clay Jr. on January 17, 1942?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c681", "question": "Layers of soil are known as what?", "answer": "Horizons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd75ae347d002c297e4c2", "question": "What is the only continent without native reptiles and snakes?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc16", "question": "What are the official United Nations languages?", "answer": "Arabic, Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c69c", "question": "Syncope is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Fainting", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b7ffb9a3a3a814d89068c67", "question": "Which singer and songwritter was born Farrokh Bulsara in 1946?", "answer": "Freddie Mercury", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feba99a7e83c707845b20d7", "question": "What is the name given to the white part of a person's eye?", "answer": "Sclera", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921a", "question": "What female singer is discussed at the start of the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b899", "question": "How many players are in the water for each team in a water polo game?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bed", "question": "What undiagnosed condition forced singer Cher to leave high school at age of 16?", "answer": "Dyslexia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26e", "question": "Who won an Oscar as Best Supporting actor in the 1993 film \"The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa4189c73aa70ea0b70b10", "question": "Which sport is strangely associated with Christmas in Venezuela?", "answer": "Many Venezuelans traditionally roller-skate during Christmas.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0c", "question": "Who played Khan in \"Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan\"?", "answer": "Ricardo Montalban", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af2e", "question": "Which London palace was destroyed by fire in 1936?", "answer": "The Crystal Palace", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e3", "question": "What plant does the vanilla bean come from?", "answer": "The orchid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f9", "question": "What is the world's largest island?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f78", "question": "What was Buddy Holly's backing band?", "answer": "The Crickets", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e5f11e3d274615ecf51453c", "question": "\"Oscitation\", is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Yawning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ed", "question": "What Harry Potter character has the patronus of a hare/bunny?", "answer": "Luna Lovegood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59a1a31a12f2a7826b9b8722", "question": "What is ornamental work in silver or gold thread or beads called?", "answer": "Filigree", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f74dfa9e54d890926f701", "question": "According to Russian law, a homeless person must be where after 10 pm?", "answer": "At home", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbf636ce05a3942286eff", "question": "The nightclub in the opening scene of the film \"Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom\" is called what?", "answer": "Club Obi-Wan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae86", "question": "What fort did Benedict Arnold promise to surrender to the British, in return for money?", "answer": "West Point", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c58", "question": "What year did singer Whitney Houston die?", "answer": "2012", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ea", "question": "What is the fin on the back of a whale called?", "answer": "Dorsal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb26865ff7d326b622a74", "question": "In the opera \"Don Giovanni\", what was Leporello job?", "answer": "Don Giovanni's Servant", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe529471bf59ab7d2e38101", "question": "What food or beverage can be made inside all British tanks?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ba", "question": "Which is the world's northernmost capital city?", "answer": "Reykjavik", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938e", "question": "Who played the role of Jim Stark in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990af23b72eedf883a8c704", "question": "What is Chopin's \"Piano Sonata in B flat minor\" also known as?", "answer": "The Funeral March", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85e", "question": "Which European country is often referred to as the \"Battlefield of Europe\"?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c373", "question": "What disease takes its name from medieval Italian words for \"bad air\"?", "answer": "Malaria", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d52", "question": "What Herman Melville character always answers \"I would prefer not to\" whenever his boss asks him to work?", "answer": "Bartleby the Scrivener", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f2616682715b82711cea", "question": "Which Canadian city is know as \"Steeltown\"?", "answer": "Hamilton, Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c873", "question": "A tetragon is geometric shape that has how many sides?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7de", "question": "The first Starbucks outside of North America was opened in what country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a162c85f01ec323f8491730", "question": "The song \"Matchmaker, Matchmaker\" came from which musical?", "answer": "Fiddler on the Roof", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d7522596a59cbdfbd3b4", "question": "Who gave the famous speech, \"Give me liberty or give me death\"?", "answer": "Patrick Henry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa34", "question": "What is the capital of Italy?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6017404244491cbd7c5a17bd", "question": "What was Vladimir Lenin's birth name?", "answer": "Vladimir Ilyich Ulyanov -- \"Lenin\" was an alias.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c207", "question": "Which country were the 1908 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f44", "question": "Who created the character of Baloo?", "answer": "Rudyard Kipling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb7", "question": "The Italian Giovanni Schiaparelli is best known today for naming most of the canals where?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96c3823c87fd04dd15e21", "question": "What Jelly Belly flavor was created for Ronald Reagan's inauguration?", "answer": "Blueberry", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba78", "question": "How many strings does the typical mandolin have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d9b3908b8581f80b092c3", "question": "What three gaming consoles did Nintendo release in 2017?", "answer": "Nintendo Switch, New Nintendo 2DS XL, and Super NES Classic Edition", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a342", "question": "What kind of a doll grabs Robbie and drags him under his bed in the 1982 film \"Poltergeist\"?", "answer": "A clown doll", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16973f7c52aae91cc07d1", "question": "In 1861, Julius Sturgis started the first US commercial bakery that made what?", "answer": "Pretzels", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cc60bb53d1af658864e0", "question": "On which three days of the week is December 25th more likely to fall?", "answer": "Tuesday, Friday or Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ded2caea2747c8aff16d42", "question": "What line on a weather map links all points of equal pressure?", "answer": "Isobar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}]